Jacob Herper

Senior Software Engineer

Coventry, United Kingdom
Phone: 07535 822221
Email: jacob@herper.uk
https://jacobherper.com
https://github.com/jakeherp
https://linkedin.com/in/jacobherper

I am a passionate Software Engineer, specialised in front-end development using React and TypeScript. As an advocate for web performance and accessibility and an evangelist for the Jamstack, I create amazing web applications to make the internet a better place.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, React, Redux, TypeScript, CSS, Styled-Components, Sass, HTML, GraphQL, REST API, Jest, Cypress, Docker, MongoDB, node.js, npm, Express, Python, VS Code, Git, GitHub, GitLab, CI/CD, TDD, BDD, Agile, Scrum

Experience

Senior Software Engineer (SDE2) - Holland & Barrett

Aug 2020 - present

TypeScript, React, Next.js, Redux, GraphQL, REST API, Jest, Cypress

- Joined Holland & Barrett as a senior software engineer, first with front-end expertise in the fulfilment squad (alongside six back-end engineers)
- Led hiring process of several further UI engineers across multiple squads
- Tech lead developing a custom-built customer services portal based on React and Next.js using TypeScript and Redux, retiring a third-party solution, saving a 6-digit sum in licence fees
- Increased non-existent test-coverage to 90+%
- Introduced e2e tests using Cypress

Senior Front-End Engineer - Dennis Publishing

Oct 2019 - Aug 2020

JavaScript, React, ES6, GraphQL, Sass, Webpack, Node.js, Express, Apollo

- Developed web applications using React, JavaScript (ES6), GraphQL and Sass
- Tech lead for the rebuild of site applications, liaising between engineering and product teams
- Optimised performance and accessibility of React applications
- Contributed to advanced error and bug tracking strategy to increase application reliability
- Improved test coverage by writing unit and integration tests with Jest and Enzyme
- Implemented platform-wide ad injection logic to work within the SSR React application and AMP pages
- Mentored more junior engineers through pair programming, code reviews and 1-on-1s

Front-End Web Developer - Raconteur

Jan 2019 - Oct 2019

TypeScript, React, Gatsby, Next.js, GraphQL, REST API, Styled-Components

- Joined as first JavaScript developer to lead the move away from WordPress-based monolithic architectures to more robust and modern React-based systems
- Developed React web applications using TypeScript, Next.js, Gatsby, GraphQL and Styled-Components with global state management through Context API
- Worked with WordPress as a headless CMS using GraphQL and REST APIs
- Developed B2B web applications for several Fortune 500 clients using vanilla JavaScript (ES6) and React
- Worked on legacy projects using ES5 JavaScript syntax with Gulp as a task runner
- Lead the redevelopment effort of a new website for Raconteur Agency
- Tech lead for several internal platform optimisations and new development projects using React and Gatsby

$\textbf{Front-End Developer} \ - \ \textit{The Specialist Works}$

Dec 2017 - Jan 2019

JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, React, Sass, WordPress, REST API

- Tech lead in design and development of new website following brand guidelines based on WordPress, PHP, HTML5, CSS and JavaScript
- Orchestrating web development work between London and Atlanta offices
- Collaborating with teams in Beijing, Dublin, New York and Bonn offices to develop custom experiences for clients across the world
- Development of a web application for a contender energy provider in collaboration with TSW Creative for critical campaign launch under time pressure
- DevOps tasks monitoring and maintaining Apache server infrastructure and DNS
- Development of PWA (React) for an event with 250+ attendees
- Collaborated with internal creative agency to deliver assets for pitches

JavaScript, PHP, Sass, HTML, React, Angular, WordPress, Drupal, Shopify, Magento

- Development of web applications for small and medium-sized businesses using JavaScript, React, PHP, Sass, HTML5, WordPress, Drupal and different e-commerce solutions
- Specialised in bespoke client solutions for London-based startups
- Design of digital assets and print products
- Management of freelance and contract engineers for international projects
- Search engine optimisation and search engine marketing

Co-Founder & CTO - Immovato GmbH, Wiesbaden, Germany

Apr 2014 - Dec 2017

Angular, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, Sass

- Built a web app to revolutionise the real estate sector in Germany
- Developed Immovato from the first concept to release of MVP
- Managed two developers (front-end and back-end) in the development of our application, initially based on Angular (JavaScript) and Laravel (PHP)
- Moved tech stack to MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js) for an improved performance and DX

Full Stack Developer & Designer - Self-Employed

Jan 2009 - Mar 2017

Angular, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, Sass

- Developed websites and web apps for small to medium-sized businesses using WordPress, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript
- Designed digital and print assets for several clients using Adobe CC (Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop)
- Managed freelancers for outsourced projects

Group Creative Director - ASA GmbH, Mainz, Germany

Jun 2008 - Oct 2014

PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MS SQL, MySQL, Sass

- Started working for ASA as a web designer and developer during final years of college, building and maintaining e-commerce websites and product landing pages
- First insights into day-to-day operations of e-commerce business (B2B and B2C)
- Design and conception of new products, packaging, brochures, advertising material
- Design and execution of international trade shows and B2B events
- Launch of UK branch of ASA Europe in Chelmsford, Essex
- Market research and legal compliance analysis for the trade of tobacco products in the United Kingdom, meetings with UK Trade & Investment and HMRC to explore importing of restricted goods
- Built retail business to become highest-grossing of its kind in the UK within 12 months

Education

CS50 - HarvardX (online education programme of Harvard University)

Jul 2020

C, Python, SQL, Algorithms, Data Structures

Full-Stack Open - University of Helsinki (online)

Sep 2019

 ${\tt React,\ JavaScript,\ Node.js,\ Express,\ GraphQL,\ Cypress,\ Jest}$

Other relevant course work - various online education programmes

2014 - present

Intermediate Python (2020), GraphQL Essentials (2020), Gatsby Static Site Generation (2019), Advanced React (2018), Advanced JavaScript (2018) Intermediate PHP (2015), Front End Web Development (2014)

Languages

English - Fluent

German - Native

Spanish - Conversational

Italian - Basic

Russian - Basic

Personal details and interests

I enjoy cooking fresh meals for my family after a long day of work. Whenever I have the opportunity I enjoy travelling to new places to experience different cultures and widen my own horizon. I also keep up-to-date with the opinions of professionals and my peers in web technologies and UX design through podcasts, conferences and Twitter.